Guide to the Oversize Manuscripts Collection 1648-2014 MS OS
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Oversize Manuscripts From Other Collections, 1714-2006
  - [Y-Nathan, Edgar J, Jr. MS 438], circa 1930s-1940s (Oversize large)
    See Edgar J. Nathan, Jr. papers finding aid for details of content.
  - [Y-Naval History Society Collection/G.V. Fox] Drawings of "The Raft" (2) (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-New York State National Guard, 9th Regiment (MS 3085)], 1858, 1864, 1944-1945 (Oversize medium)
    Holds oversize items from the 9th Regiment collection (MS 3085). See that finding aid for details of content.
  - [Y-Ogden, David], 1811-1815 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Olds, Irving S.] Woodbury Subdivision, 1930-1940 (Oversize large)
    Contains oversize maps and blueprints about property Olds owned in Nassau County, New York. There are references to his property being involved in the construction of the Northern State Parkway.
  - [Y-Olcott, Eben. Papers] Maps of Peru and Panama, Undated (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Pelton, William Snow] Certificates, 1826-1830 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Phelps Papers] Diplomas and Correspondence, 1855-1877 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Pickhardt Papers] Photographs of Otto and others at a Russian Prisioner's of War Camp, Sagan, Germany, 1919 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Robert Price papers (MS 3130)] John V. Lindsay congressional campaign posters, 1958-1964 (Oversize large)
    ELECT / JOHN LINDSAY / [portrait] / REPUBLICAN CANDIDATE / FOR CONGRESS / VOTE ROW A [1 copy]
    VOTE FOR / GOVERNOR ROCKEFELLER'S TEAM! / FOR CONGRESS - 17TH DISTRICT / JOHN LINDSAY / FOR CONGRESS - 19TH DISTRICT / RICHARD S. ALDRICH / FOR STATE SENATOR / JOSEPH PINTO / FOR ASSEMBLYMAN / PAUL J. CURRAN / VOTE ROW "A" ALL THE WAY [1 copy]
    RE-ELECT / CONGRESSMAN JOHN V. / [portrait] / LINDSAY / OUTSTANDING PUBLIC SERVANT / VOTE ROW A [4 copies]
  - [Y-Robert Price papers (MS 3130)] John V. Lindsay mayoral campaign posters, 1965 (Oversize large)
    Dirty air. / Dirty lungs. / Dirty laundry. / He'll do / something / about air pollution/ ELECT / JOHN / LINDSAY / MAYOR / Vote the Lindsay Team / Lindsay-Mollen-Costello [1 copy, on stiff cardboard]
    "He is fresh and everyone else is tired." / VOTE FOR / JOHN LINDSAY / FOR MAYOR [full length portrait in two parts]
    Milton Mollen / FOR COMPTROLLER / [portrait] / Elect Lindsay/Mollen/Costello [1 copy]
  - [Y-Rogers Family Papers] Newspaper articles relating to the Rogers family, Undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Rogers Family Papers] Certificate from Massachusetts Charitable Merchants Association Awarding Silver Medal to Rogers Statutettes, 1890 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Rogers Family Papers] Bound volume 1 and copies of Country Life Magazine, 1921 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Rogers Family Papers] Accompanying letters, notes, and articles from bound volume no.1, Undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Rogers Family Papers] Drafts of Rogers family trees, Undated (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Ruggles, George D.], 1855-1893 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Saint Andrews Society] Membership certificates, 1889, 1926 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Scoppetta, Nicholas. Papers] Big Apple poster and Children's Aid Society award certificate, 1976, 1993 (Oversize large)
    Poster: The Big Apple / You have to be a little crazy to live in New York, but you'd be nuts to live anywhere else. April '76; inscribed "To my good friend Nick Scoppetta / With great affection and warm regards / Abe Beame."
    Award certificate: Children's Aid Society / Presented by the / Trustees / to / Nicholas Scoppetta / President / 1987-1993; with a reproduction of a historic photograph of children playing in a tenement-lined street.
  - [Y-7th Regiment Records] Series XIV: Panoramic Views, 1893-1917 (Oversize large)
    Nine photographs:
    Zurich (1893)
    7th Regiment, Peekskill Camp (1911 June)
    First Brigade NYNG Camp at Orange, Connecticut Maneuver Campaign (1912 Aug. 10-19)
    West Point Parade Ground (1914)
    McAllen, Texas (1916 Aug. 8)
    McAllen, Texas (1916 Sep. 6)
    McAllen, Texas (1916)
    Madero, Texas (1916)
    Camp Wadsworth, Spartanburg, SC (1917)
  - [Y-Scriba, Frederick and George] Certificates, 1790-1816 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Sharman, William. MS 3068] (8 items), 1916-1949 (Oversize medium)
    Photographs (3 panoramas) | McAllen, Texas |1916
    Photograph (1 print) | "Living Insignia | of the | Twenty-Seventh Division | "New York's Own" | Breakers of the Hindenburg Line. | Formed of 10,000 Officers and Enlisted Men | Major-General John R. O'Ryan, Commanding." | 1919
    Photographs (3 prints) | Manufacturers Trust, Featherbed Lane (Bronx) | 1949
    Award | Office of Price Administration | 1944
  - [Y-Shepard, Helen Miller Gould Papers] Certificates, 1859-1910 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Ships and Shipping Collection (MS 563)] (Oversize small)
    See the finding aid for the New-York Historical Society ships and shipping collection (MS 563) for item content.
  - [Y-Ships and Shipping Collection (MS 563)] (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Ship Bombay] Letters of Marque, 1810-1813 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Squier, E.G.] Sketches of Lancaster Castle, 1867 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Staten Island Papers], 1810-1899 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Stevens, Ebenezer. Papers] Commission, 1798 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Stewart, William George. MS 594]. Exports from New York to Mexico., 1841 (Oversize large)
    Oversize documents from the Stewart papers. See William George Stewart, MS 594, finding aid.
  - [Y-Stoutenburgh Family] Copies, Undated (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Stoutenburgh Family] Original Documents, 1741-1806 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Stoutenburgh Family] Family Tree (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Strong Family Papers] Deeds, 1803-1819 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Strong Family Papers] Deeds, 1790 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Strong Family Papers] Deeds, 1784-1815 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Taylor, Jack papers (MS 3150)] Tammany Hall (2 folders), 2014-2016, n.d. (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Thursby, Emma. Papers] Documents, 1802-1909 (Oversize small)
  - [Y- 1914 Time Capsule Collection] Newspapers, 1914 May (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Ulster County, N.Y.], 1676-1730 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Ulster County, N.Y.], 1710-1750 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Ulster County, N.Y.], 1719 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Ulster County, N.Y.], 1719-1721 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Ulster County, N.Y.], 1720 July 7 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Ulster County, N.Y.], 1720 July 7 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Ulster County, N.Y.], 1720 July 7 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Ulster County, N.Y.], 1739-1759 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Ulster County, N.Y.], 1750 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Ulster County, N.Y.], 1759 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Ulster County, N.Y.], 1762-1814 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Ulster County, N.Y.], 1778 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Van Cortlandt Papers] Inheritance- Peter and Cornelia Van Dyck, 1719 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Van Ness-Philip Papers] Appointments, 1905-1930 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Van Ness-Philip Papers] Certificates, 1856-1938 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Van Ness-Philip Papers] Certificates, Photographs, Map, 1876-1935 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Van Renssalaer] Van Renssalaer Manor/Watervlidt, ca 1863 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Walton Family], 1704-1804 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Walton Family], 1707-1798 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-Walton Family], 1708 April 22 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Walton Family], 1720-1806 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Walton Family], 1768 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-Webb, George Creighton] Silver Star for Gallantry, 1918 July 9 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Whelpley, Abigail Belden. MS 3067], 1824 (Oversize small)
    Indenture. See Abigail Belden Whelpley papers finding aid for detail.
  - [Y-White, Richard Grant] Sheet Music, Undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-White, Richard Grant] Sheet Music, Undated (Oversize small)